Mikhail Zharnikov

DevOps and Full Stack Engineer

I am dedicated, full-stack developer with 10 years experiences. I worked as frontend developer for 2 years, full-stack developer for 6 years, software engineer for 4 years. Now I am mainly specialized in fullstack development.

Working with many companies and doing enterprise and medium-sized projects with clients since graduate, was the chance to gain so much professional experiences and to learn and to practice how to develop projects in reality.

I am very creative and new-technology starter.

I am also very fast learner on the new technologies that looks good.

So when new thing comes, I learnt it first and implement it in the appropriate aspects in the development.

As a matter of fact, I started AngularJS when it was announced in 2010, ReactJS when it was announced in 2013 and VueJS in 2014. Very positive and energetic in new technologies, if the project involves new technology, that's no problem in the development to me. I am dedicated, self-discipline, energetic creative developer with perfect result. I have passed all the exams relevant to these skills on upwork with good mark so I guarantee the skill. Once the contract is started, I lead it to success. I can provide you up to 80 hours a week and have no barriers in communication. Show less Show less of Mikhail's summary

Experience

2007-04 -

Web Developer

2011-08

ProfitDV

- Solved tickets raised by clients based on HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery and frameworks such as EmberJS and HandlebarsJS.
- Extensively worked on subroutines for different APIs using NodeJS and Python, modifying and creating new connections to Database. Worked on internal tool which is purely based on PHP.
- Using AJAX calls through HandlebarsJS and EmberJS to populate the data tables on the front-end.
- Using AJAX, JSON with JQuery for request data and response processing.
- Tracked and solved tickets for detects on bug reporting tool (JIRA and ASANA)
- Using Putty for debugging and connect to my remote files in securely using SSH Encryption (public key and private key) and WinSCP to transfer files between local and remote folders and change file permissions.

2013-03 -2015-01

Full Stack Developer (Remote)

JackInTheBox

- Built and maintained GUIs using ReactJS/AngularJS/NodeJS to provide usability to business operations data.
- Established a level of standardization for UIs across the Business Process Management team.
- Database Architecture and Administration
- Tools used here: Oracle, Hibernate, RestFUL Web Services, Spring, Agile Methodology, Confluence, Jira, NodeJS, Flask, Python

2013-01 -2017-04

Senior Full Stack Engineer

Febno Technologies

- Created endpoints and functionality for the new dashboards on the back end and engineered logic on front end pages to gather and display the data.
- Developed multiple RESTful API's, using Python-Flask, Node-Express, Golang, Ruby on Rails and exposed infrastructure utilization, active processes, and configuration reports on ReactJS/AngularJS based pages.



Personal Info

Address

Amurskiy Bulvar 55/2

Khabarovsk, Khabarovsk Krai

Russia

Phone

+7 (914) 3164890

E-mail

mikhailZharnikovPro@gmail.com

Date of birth 1989-02-19

custom

https://www.facebook.com/mikhail.z

harnikov.5

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mikhailzharnikov-b65076156/



- Implemented enterprise web applications and CMS based solutions using frameworks like Django, WooCommerce, Wagtail, October and Symphony.
- Assisted as a consultant in the design and implementation of the several projects, from journal management systems to Enterprise Resource Planning(ERP) solutions.
- Developed a home services web app using react using react with an AWS lambda and Dynamo DB backend that allowed in-home specialist to gather structured and unstructured data on customer's homes.
- Coordinated core server product development in Spring MVC and Spring SOA service components for deployment to 200+ client sites, ensuring compatibility with all major browsers on mobile and desktop platforms
- Worked in 3rd-party API integrations with Amazon, Rewardstyle, and ShopBazaar developed with TDD principles.

2017-09 present

Full Stack Engineer

Upwork

Working with the amazing clients over the world and led all the projects into success.

- MEAN and MERN, LAMP Stack Development
- Continuous integration (Jenkins/Hudson) and version control (SVN, Git,
- Build difficult indecies and queris in ElasticSearch analyses, n-gram, multifield searchin, etc.
- Design and deploy API specification with testing case(Swagger). - Troubleshooted issues affecting production, stage, and development
- environments as requested.



Education

2007-04 -2011-05

Novosibirsk State University (NSU)

Bachelor degree in Computer Science, 4 years course Programming environments and methodologies for the design, development,

- testing, and maintenance of large software systems. Develop a substantial software product from requirements to delivery using
- disciplined techniques. Assembly language programming, assemblers, linkers, loaders. Computer

architecture including digital logic, processor organization, instruction sets,

- addressing techniques, virtual memory, microprogramming. Computer networks, layering standards, communication fundamentals, error detection and recovery, queuing theory, delay versus throughput trade-offs in
- networks, multiple-access channels, design issues in wide and local area networks. Theories, formalisms, techniques to emulate intelligent behavior using information processing models. Symbolic programming, search, problem solving, knowledge-based techniques, logic, and theorem proving. Optional

topics: natural language processing, machine learning, and computer vision.

https://github.com/mikhailzharnikov

Personal Website

http://mikhailzharnikov.herokuapp.com/

mikhailZharnikovPro@gmail.com



DevOps

Advanced

Amazon Web Services

Advanced

Augmented Reality

Advanced

Machine Learning

CMS Development

Google Cloud Platform

Intermediate

Mobile App Development

Advanced

Advanced

Advanced